Abdullah Al Masud

Mobile App Developer (Android & Flutter)



- ♥ Flat-A2, House-5, Road-5, Block-C, Section-6, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216.
- almasud.arm@gmail.com
- ****01737606053
- **?** GitHub □

SUMMARY

Software engineer with experience in the mobile application development industry, specializing in creating native Android and Flutter-based mobile applications. Extensive background in these areas enables the production of high-quality, efficient mobile solutions to meet specific client needs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering

Dhaka International University ☐ 2015 – 2019 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

SKILLS

Language

Java, Kotlin, XML, Dart, Python, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3, Basic Swift.

Library

Jetpack compose, Hilt, Bloc, GetIt, RxJava, Retrofit, Google Map etc.

Development Tools

Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, XCode, Git, Postman, Jira.

Database

MySQL, SQLite, Firebase Realtime & Firestore.

Operating Systems

MacOS, MS Windows, Android, Linux (Ubuntu)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NybSys Inc.

Software Engineer (Android & Flutter)

09/2021 - present | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- · Android application development
- Flutter application development

XOR Geek

Mobile Application Engineer (Android & Flutter)

09/2020 - 09/2021 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Android application development
- Flutter application development
- Web application development

PROJECTS

• **Xtreme VPN** □: A mobile app for Android platform where you experience unparalleled online security and freedom with Xtreme VPN, Xtreme VPN stands as a fortress to safeguard your digital presence.

Build tools: Android, Java, Kotlin, RestAPI etc.

• **DrinkWell** □: A mobile app for Android & iOS platform where a Pump operator can register a water ATM card for a user, recharge to the user's water ATM card, daily report etc. through the app.

Build with: Flutter, RestAPI, NFC tag reader ${\it etc.}$

• **Sentra PTT** □: A PTT (Push to Talk) mobile app for Android platform that connects your team instantly. Its rich media features, alerts, photos, location sharing, calls & messaging provide this app the greatest power.

 $\label{eq:build tools: Android, Java, Protocol Buffers, Retrofit, RoomDB \ {\tt etc.}$

• **Hokkaido Classic Golf Club App** \square : A mobile app for Android platform that dedicated for a Golf Club. a registered member of the club can access and use the app.

Build tools: Android, Java, Retrofit etc.

- One-Click Order App □: A mobile app for Android/iOS platform where a registered member by the company can access the app and can order products by using the app. Build tools: Flutter
- One-Click Order App API & Admin Panel □: A web app that provides the API for the mobile app and manage the products, members and their orders through mobile app.

 Build tools: Laravel, Bootstrap etc.
- **Augmented Learn** □: An educational app for Android platform that helps to teach preschool children with Augmented Reality. **Build tools**: **Android**, **Java**, **ARCore**, Adobe **photoshop**, **Blender** etc.